How high up is space? Actually, if you
started running straight up at an
average running pace, it would take you
48 minutes to reach the point where
there's no longer enough air for you to
breathe. It would take you an hour to
get to the height planes fly. It would
take you 8 hours to reach the line that
NASA defines as space, but it would take
you 10 hours to reach the Carmen line,
which basically everyone else defines as
space. Just above this line is where
Blue Origin has taken passengers. You'd
reach that in another 20 to 30 minutes.
If you kept going for 16 total hours,
you'd reach some of the lowest
satellites orbiting Earth. In 40 hours,
you'd reach the ISS. At 55 hours, you'd
reach the average altitude of Starlink
satellites. And after 3,500 hours, or
almost 146 days of running, you'd reach
the farthest satellites orbiting Earth.
For more optimistic science and tech
stories, subscribe.